# **LEWIS SAUNDERS - ITV**

## **Frontend Engineer**

**\** 07426774243

@ lewissaunders100@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lewissaunders/

**?** Farnborough, Hampshire

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced Front End Engineer with a strong proficiency in modern front end technologies. Focused on JavaScript, React.js, Next.js and TypeScript. Experienced with all Agile development methodologies such as Kanban, Scrum and Scrumban. Highly driven, motivated and quick to pick up new technologies, with a proven track record developing visible front-end services to strict deadlines.

### **SKILLS**

#### Languages

JavaScript TypeScript HTML/CSS Ruby SQL Python PHP

#### Libraries/Frameworks/Other Technologies

React.js	Next	js N	MySQL		Se	elenium	Capyba	ra Cu	Cucumber		ul APIs	GraphQL
UX/UI Figma		Git	Jenki	Jenkins		AWS Docker		DevTools		Postman	SitePrism	
BrowserStack		Tizen Studio		Android Studio		XCode	Redis	Lau	nchDarkly	PNPM		
Agile Development Scrum					ban							

## **STRENGTHS**



### **Self-Starter**

Consistency taking sole responsibility for tasks, bugs or potential UI improvements that I observe. I believe independent working is equally important as teamwork, and I pride myself on taking the incentive to take full ownership of my work



### **Supportive**

I ensure that my colleagues are aware of my willingness to assist them when they needed. Whether that be unblocking their technical barriers, or being an active listener. I believe supportive team work in this way leads to better results and a stronger team moral.

## **EXPERIENCE**

06/2022 - Present •

## Frontend Engineer

London

#### ITV

- Taking part in the development of responsive and user-friendly web applications, ensuring a seamless user experience across these different applications working on ITVX Browser, ITVX Connected TV & the ITV News website.
- · Collaborating with UX/UI designers to translate design mockups and wireframes into quality code.
- Being a lead developer and primary driving force for multiple projects that are currently live on ITVX. These include the Regional News functionality which went live onto ITVX December 2023.
   And the news/sport short form & category page. This work can be seen on the ITVX app on both connected TV and browser.
- Frequently contributing & maintaining the ITV News website which is interacted with by thousands on a monthly basis.
- · Being a significant part of the ITV Hub to ITVX rebrand from start to finish.
- · Optimise website performance through code and asset optimisation.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### 10/2020 - 06/2022 •

# Software Development Engineer in Test

London

- Oversee the QA process for Account Management on the ITV Hub.
- Solely recreating an entire codebase, which contained all acceptance tests for video related features on the ITV Hub, from the ground up. This was due to the old codebase being very outdated. This codebase is now used on the daily by the video team to ensure all video related functionality works as expected.
- · Contributing to, and maintaining, automated testing frameworks for ITV web & mobile applications, ensuring comprehensive coverage of functional and non-functional requirements.
- · Develop and maintain automated test scripts using industry-standard tools and frameworks.
- · Participate in code reviews, conduct root cause analysis for defects, and work collaboratively with developers to resolve issues and improve overall product quality.

#### 09/2019 - 10/2020

# Technology Graduate

London

#### ltv

- · Rotate around a variety of different departments to obtain a deeper understanding of different technology stacks and to understand the infrastructure of ITV, gaining context on how different teams/departments work together.
- · Example placements include: System Infrastructure, Cybersecurity, ITV Studios, ITV Sales Technologies & Data Science.
- · Installing and configuring a malware analysis machine for the Cybersecurity team. This machine acts as an isolated environment that does not touch the ITV network, in which potentially malicious files can be opened.

#### 05/2017 - 08/2018

Data Analyst

Bracknell, Berkshire

**IRi Worldwide** 

07/2016 - 03/2017

Assistant Manager & Pharmacy Advisor

Camberley, Surrey Boots UK

10/2016 - 12/2016

Entertainments Performer

Merlin Entertainments

09/2015 - 01/2016

Bartender

Birmingham

Staines, Surrey

**The Green Man** 

## **EDUCATION**

01/2018 - 01/2019 •

MSc Computer Science

Kent University of Kent

01/2012 - 01/2016

B.Sc. Biological Sciences with a Year in Computer Science
University of Birmingham

Birmingham

01/2005 - 01/2012

Camberley, Surrey

A-Levels - Maths (A\*) Biology (A) Physics (A) Computing (A) GCSEs - 10 A\*s - Bs

**Collingwood College**